<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://xrl1.sh/</id><title>A collection of various tech blabs</title><subtitle>Just a blog about tech like Linux kernel, Cyber Security research, Machine Learning, and more. </subtitle> <updated>2024-12-17T23:52:44+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Lior Ribak</name> <uri>https://xrl1.sh/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://xrl1.sh/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://xrl1.sh/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2024 Lior Ribak </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>The Next Generation of Sensitive Data Detection</title><link href="https://xrl1.sh/posts/the-next-generation-of-sensitive-information-detection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Next Generation of Sensitive Data Detection" /><published>2024-12-01T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>https://xrl1.sh/posts/the-next-generation-of-sensitive-information-detection/</id> <content src="https://xrl1.sh/posts/the-next-generation-of-sensitive-information-detection/" /> <author> <name>Lior Ribak</name> </author> <category term="Cyber Security" /> <summary> About 6 months ago, I resigned from my comfortable Engineering Manager position to explore new opportunities. After some rest and vacation time, I wondered what to do next. I have always been drawn to indie hacking, so I started brainstorming ideas - “Hey, I’ve spent years applying machine learning to catch cyber bad guys… what if I could turn that experience into my own product?” I wasn’t in... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>The AI Trend - LLMs and Generative AI for Everyone</title><link href="https://xrl1.sh/posts/the-ai-trend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The AI Trend - LLMs and Generative AI for Everyone" /><published>2023-06-19T15:21:20+03:00</published> <updated>2023-06-19T15:21:20+03:00</updated> <id>https://xrl1.sh/posts/the-ai-trend/</id> <content src="https://xrl1.sh/posts/the-ai-trend/" /> <author> <name>Lior Ribak</name> </author> <category term="Machine Learning" /> <summary> We are just in the middle of 2023, but it will be known as the year were the mass public has begun accessing and using AI. Whether or not AI will take over a lot of aspects of our life or fall into a more proportional and practical usage is yet to be known. In this post I’ll try to explain what wheels are turning in the tech industry that drives this revolution and how to jump on this LLM trai... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Creating Real-World AI Models by Newbies With ChatGPT</title><link href="https://xrl1.sh/posts/coordinates-model-with-ChatGPT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating Real-World AI Models by Newbies With ChatGPT" /><published>2023-01-28T11:21:07+02:00</published> <updated>2023-01-29T14:17:33+02:00</updated> <id>https://xrl1.sh/posts/coordinates-model-with-ChatGPT/</id> <content src="https://xrl1.sh/posts/coordinates-model-with-ChatGPT/" /> <author> <name>Lior Ribak</name> </author> <category term="Machine Learning" /> <summary> After ChatGPT came out, I challenged it greatly - with riddles, general questions, and lots of code-generation tasks. It stood firm for most of my dares, and even when it didn’t, it still pretended to know the answer and provided a detailed wrong explanation, the same behavior as many of my coworkers. After a while, it became a major tool in my arsenal, to the extent that whenever I open a new ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Big data for Dummy Developers - Step Into Foreign Territory</title><link href="https://xrl1.sh/posts/how-to-send-big-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big data for Dummy Developers - Step Into Foreign Territory" /><published>2022-12-18T00:23:21+02:00</published> <updated>2022-12-19T11:06:17+02:00</updated> <id>https://xrl1.sh/posts/how-to-send-big-data/</id> <content src="https://xrl1.sh/posts/how-to-send-big-data/" /> <author> <name>Lior Ribak</name> </author> <category term="Big Data" /> <summary> So it happens that in about the past year and a bit, I repositioned to a Big Data Engineer role in my company without any prior knowledge. I had been writing data pipelines - primarily Spark Applications in Scala, deployed over k8s infrastructure. After dealing with those scary words and some others (Iceberg, Data lake, parquet, Kafka, Helm charts, and more), I can say I have learned a lot, an... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>My Simple Utility for Kernel Function Graph Tracing</title><link href="https://xrl1.sh/posts/kernel_tracer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Simple Utility for Kernel Function Graph Tracing" /><published>2022-01-10T20:39:22+02:00</published> <updated>2022-01-10T20:39:22+02:00</updated> <id>https://xrl1.sh/posts/kernel_tracer/</id> <content src="https://xrl1.sh/posts/kernel_tracer/" /> <author> <name>Lior Ribak</name> </author> <category term="Linux" /> <summary> Have you ever wondered how come strace is such a popular tool, while all it shows you are only the syscalls a program is calling and nothing more? Well, in most cases it’s enough. But sometimes, even rarely, a programmer will also want to inspect what happens under the kernel’s hood inside the syscalls. I have been investigating kernel behavior on some basic tasks, like module loading for exa... </summary> </entry> </feed>
